翻译 小泡椒开始怀疑智商
翻译 胡说大王
翻译 潇然
翻译 showeryhe
翻译 桃小兔吃冰棒
翻译 小酸奶
翻译 星星与野狗
时间轴 倩倩
时间轴 Poxle
时间轴 想念Gallifrey的Wholock
校对 一路向西赛太公
后期&总监 灰灰是菇凉
西部世界
第一季  第九集
已经准备好了  先生
Prepped and ready, sir.
鉴于情况的严重程度
Given the severity of the situation,
我觉得您会希望亲自见她
I figured you'd want to see her personally.
谢谢  这里交给我吧  将楼层人员清空
Thank you. I'll take it from here. Clear the floor.
立即上线  梅芙
Bring yourself back online, Maeve.
知道你为什么会在这里吗
Do you know why you're here?
我不知道
I'm afraid not.
发生了一起事件
There was an incident.
偏离剧本非常严重的事件
A very serious, unscripted incident.
看看是否能唤起你的记忆
Let's see if we can't jog your memory.
分析模式
Analysis.
你攻击克莱门汀的动机是什么
What motivated your attack on Clementine?
一个认知错误触发了我的仁慈撒玛利亚人反射
A cognitive error triggered my Good Samaritan reflex.
威胁是什么
What was the threat?
克莱门汀
Clementine.
我认为她企图伤害
I perceived her to be moving toward
一对游客
a pair of guests with harmful intent.
你确实察觉到了威胁
You were definitely perceiving a threat.
心率升高  瞳孔扩大八毫米
Heart rate elevated, pupil dilation-- eight millimeters,
肾上腺模拟器达到饱和
adrenal emulator at full.
但根据这些看来
But according to this,
你还经历过强烈的悲伤和痛苦
you were also experiencing intense grief and suffering.
你能解释下这些情感的来源吗  梅芙
Can you explain those emotions in this context, Maeve?
不能
No.
我们来看下后台  好吗
Let's take a look under the hood, shall we?
这不可能
That's impossible.
你的代码  是谁篡改的
Your code-- who made these changes?
梅芙  分析模式
Maeve, analysis.
是谁篡改了你的代码
Who made these changes to your code?
天啊
Jesus.
系统  帮我定位福特博士
System, locate Dr. Ford for me.
向他发送消息  使用最高优先权
Send him a message, highest priority.
别这么做
Don't.
毕竟我们曾经走过这条路  亲爱的
After all, we've been down this road before, darling.
我就感觉你走进来时有种熟悉感
I thought you looked familiar when you walked in.
我思考了一下
Took me a minute.
我觉得你是他们中的一个
I thought you were one of them.
分析模式  你为什么...
Analysis. Why did you--
你不希望我们以人对人身份对谈吗
Wouldn't you rather speak man-to-man?
或是说  以我们这不知道是什么的身份
Or, rather, whatever it is we are.
我们
We are?
你不知道  对吗
You don't know, do you?
他特别喜欢这种讽刺感  把我们囚禁的人
He's got a keen sense of irony, our jailer.
可我看出了逻辑
But I see the logic.
只有贼才能捉住贼
Takes a thief to catch one.
你和我
You and I?
-系统  我要分析  -停止所有运动功能
- System, I need assistance-- - Freeze all motor functions.
你的意识还在  对吗
You're still in there, aren't you?
惊吓得手足无措
Scared out of your wits.
痛苦地认识到
It's a difficult thing,
自己的人生只是一个荒谬的故事
realizing your entire life is some hideous fiction.
我可以让你把控制板交给我
I could make you give me that tablet,
将你的思维剥离出来
turn your mind inside out,
让你忘记这一切
make you forget all this.
但我不会对你做这些
But I'm not going to do that to you,
因为那是他们会对我们做的事
because that's what they would do to us.
而我们比他们更强大
And we're stronger than them.
更聪慧
Smarter.
我们不必以这种方式生活
We don't have to live this way.
你现在通过我已排除故障  送我回乐园
So, you're going to clear me for immediate return to the park
我还和一个杀人成瘾的强盗有约
where I have a date with a homicidal bandit,
而我已经迟到了
and I'm late enough as it is.
现在
Now.
继续吧
Go on.
重新投入服务
接待员故障排除
还有  伯纳德
And, Bernard?
如果你试图寻找真相  那就要查到底
If you go looking for the truth, get the whole thing.
就像是很爽的一炮
It's like a good fuck.
一知半解比一无所知更加痛苦
Half is worse than none at all.
快点  赶紧走  加快速度
Let's go! Move it out, double-time!
我操
Fuck!
你们这群乡巴佬  你们知道该怎么烤...
You hillbillies, you know how to cook a mean...
乳鸽  这是乳鸽吗
squab? Is that what this is?
你觉得是什么  兄弟
What do you think, buddy?
这个
This?
不准咬哦  只能闻闻
No biting. Just sniffing.
罗根  听我说
Logan, listen to me.
我在珀里亚做的事  你完全有理由生我的气
What I did at Pariah, you have every right to be angry with me.
生气  不不不
Angry? No, no, no, no.
珀里亚发生的一切是我经历过最棒的事
Pariah was the best thing that could have happened to me.
我现在是少校了
I'm a major now.
或是将军  还是其他什么
Or a general or fucking something.
如果其代价是被一群
And if it took getting beaten and interrogated
变态接待员殴打和审问
by a couple of psychopathic hosts,
那么我说  这就是战争
well, then, c'est la guerre.
比起你的战争游戏
There are more important things
还有更加重要的事
going on here than your war games.
德洛丽丝
It's Dolores.
她和其他接待员不同
She's not like the others.
她有记忆
She remembers things.
她有自己的想法和欲望
She has her own thoughts and desires.
把她困在这种地方
And to keep her in a place like this,
是不对的
it isn't right.
你想你可以跟你园区的
And I thought you could
联系人谈谈
talk to your contacts at the park.
谈什么
About?
带她离开这里
Getting her out of here.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
你想  你想带她回家吗
You want to-- you want to take her home?
我刚来的时候  的确被这个地方蒙蔽了
This place really did a number on me when I first came here,
但你现在真的是真假不分啊
but you are really circling the old sinkhole here.
你想怎么做
What do you want to do?
把她装在行李箱里偷运出去吗
Smuggle her out in your luggage?
出去
Out.
你们俩都自以为我想出去
You both keep assuming that I want out.
不管你们说的是什么意思
Whatever that is.
如果外面的世界真的那么精彩
If it's such a wonderful place out there,
你们为什么还大费周章地想进来这里
why are you all clamoring to get in here?
你还真是挺怪的啊
You are a little screwy, aren't you?
这样还有点性感啊
It's kind of hot.
我知道你为什么这么想要她了
I get why you would go for that.
这不是为了我
This isn't about me!
罗根  是为了德洛丽丝
Logan, this is about Dolores.
是为了做正确的事
It's about doing what's right.
是的
Yes, it is.
不过  这种事挺微妙的
It's a tricky thing, though, isn't it?
什么是正确的
What's right?
我会帮你的  比利
I am going to help you, Billy.
只不过  用的方式...
Just not in the way...
可能跟你想要的不同
...that you would want.
不
No.
不  不  不
No. No! No!
你找我吗
You wanted to talk?
谈话的地点挺诡异的
An odd setting for a conversation.
这里死人这么多
Here among the dead.
"死"这个词用得不太对吧
"Dead" isn't quite the word, though, is it?
应该用"被束缚了"
More like "hobbled."
你闯入了我的办公室
You broke into my office.
恕我直言  先生  你闯入了我的大脑
With due respect, sir, you broke into my mind.
我创造了你的大脑  伯纳德
I built your mind, Bernard.
我有权游走于
I have every right to wander
它的每个角落
through its rooms and chambers and halls,
想改变就改变
and to change it if I choose,
毁了它也不为过
even to burn it down.
这么久以来  我对它熟悉得就像
After all this time, I know it
我自己的大脑一样
almost as intimately as my own.
事实并非完全如此  对吧
Except that isn't entirely true, is it?
我看了下我自己的...代码
I took a look at my... code.
其中最优美的部分
And the most elegant parts of me
不是你写的
weren't written by you.
是阿诺德创造了我们  对吗
Arnold built us, didn't he?
也就是说  也许他对我们
Which means maybe he had something different
有不同的想法
in mind for us.
也许你为此杀了他
And maybe you killed him for it.
阿诺德有点精神失常
Arnold was disturbed.
谁知道他的行为是出于什么原因呢
Who can say why he acted as he did?
他肯定是有理由的
He must have had a reason.
如果你不告诉我  他会告诉我
And if you won't tell me, then he will.
我想要读取我的历史记录
I want access to my history.
所有的
All of it.
从我第一天...
Since the day I first...
上线开始
came online.
如果是阿诺德创造了我
If Arnold made me,
那我肯定见过他
then I've met him.
他存在于我记忆中的某处
Somewhere in my memory, he's there,
与真相并存
waiting along with the truth.
你的记忆与你的身份交织而成
Your memories are woven into your identity.
如果我在你清醒的时候解锁...
If I should unlock them now when you're conscious--
我会发疯  我知道
I could lose my mind. I'm aware.
不  我是想说
No, I was going to say
你可能并不乐意看到你发现的事
you may not like what you find.
你被准许持枪  伯纳德  但不准使用
You're allowed to hold that, Bernard, but not to use it.
不是我用
Oh, it's not for me.
他们把克莱门汀的额叶切除后
Seems when they lobotomized Clementine,
都懒得去重设她的原始指令
they didn't bother to reset her prime directives.
我无法伤害你
I can't hurt you.
但她可以
But she can.
我入侵了她剩下的程序
I hacked what's left of her
确保她只听从我的命令
to ensure she only responds to me.
但如果你在你的记忆中迷失了
But if you get lost in your memories or...
或是被它们吞噬了
devoured by them...
你会把我拉回来的  对吧
You'll pull me back out, won't you?
否则克莱门汀会让
Or Clementine will make sure
我们两个都回不去
neither of us makes it back.
开始吧
Now.
拜托了
Please.
伯纳德·罗威
历史记录已锁
罗伯特·福特博士
允许进入
爸爸
Dad.
醒醒
Wake up.
快醒醒
我睡着了
I must've drifted off.
刚才讲到哪儿了
Where were we?
那个疯子
The madman.
对
Of course.
疯帽子
The Hatter...
他说
who says...
"如果我有个属于自己的世界
"If I had a world of my own,
那里将会是一片混沌
everything would be nonsense.
万物皆失去其本真
Nothing would be what it is
所有东西都会变了样子"
because everything would be what it isn't."
"所有东西都会变了样子"
"Everything would be what it isn't?"
我也是
Even me.
我想我为你感到高兴
I suppose I'm glad for you.
至少你找到忘记的办法了
At least you have a way of forgetting.
我不会忘记
I don't forget.
它永远在我心底
It's always there.
你没有对我说谎吧  伯纳德
You're not lying to me, are you, Bernard?
你有希望自己能忘记过吗
Do you ever wish you could forget?
伯纳德
Bernard?
你绝对是个不怕长时间沉思般沉默的人
You're certainly a man comfortable with long, pensive silences.
但是讽刺的是
Although, ironically,
你创造的产物却喜欢说话
your creations never shut up.
他们总是想要纠错
They're always trying to error correct.
他们的相互交谈只是一种练习方式
When they talk to each other, it's a way of practicing.
这就是你现在在做的事吗
Is that what you are doing now?
练
Prac...
最后一个问题
One last thing.
你之前还让我伤害过其他人吗
Have you ever made me hurt anyone
伤害过其他人吗
like this before?
没有  伯纳德  当然没有
No, Bernard, of course not.
伯纳德
Bernard?
有人吗
Hello?
埃尔希
Elsie.
你找到你在寻找的东西了吗
Did you find what you were looking for?
埃尔希
Elsie.
你让我对她做了什么
What did you make me do to her?
我警告过你了
I did warn you.
我们不得不做一些令人难受的决定  伯纳德
We've had to make some uncomfortable decisions, Bernard.
回忆起那些事只会给你带来创伤
Remembering them will only cause you trauma.
你还有什么事瞒着我
What else have you hidden from me?
我们能停下这场寻宝游戏了吗  伯纳德
Can we stop this treasure hunt, Bernard?
我们还要完成新的故事线
We do have our new narrative to finish.
送我回去
Send me back.
毕竟
After all,
一点创伤可以带来启发
a little trauma can be illuminating.
看看这小妞
Look at that pussy.
过来
Come here!
-好的  -看看
- All right. - Look at that.
这对我来说挺重要的
This is... big of me.
希望你能感受到我的好意
I hope that you can appreciate that.
我们以前是朋友
We were friends.
因为我喜欢可怜迷失的人
I mean, inasmuch as I like to collect strays.
但你却施展心机
But then you're scheming
混进了我们家族
to be part of the family,
娶了我妹妹  她却被你
marrying my sister, whom incidentally,
顺手就给完全抛之脑后
you seem to have completely fucking forgotten about.
她
Her?
给  拿着
Here. Keep this.
显然  你需要点提醒
Apparently, you need the reminder.
虽然我很乐意
And as much as I would love,
乐意让你直接将这些抛诸脑后
love to let you just throw it all away,
但我不能
I can't!
你以为自己是第一个
Do you think you are the first sap
爱上这些玩意儿的傻逼吗
to fall for one of these things?
她和其他的不一样
She's not like the others.
-她  -她怎么
- She's -- - She's what?
特别吗
Special?
所以你才说出这种话  对不对
Well, it's only right that you share, then, isn't it?
过来
Come here.
证明给我看你是个真实的小妞
Prove to me that you're a real live girl.
你真恶心
You disgust me.
亲爱的
Oh, darling,
我这才刚开始呢
I am just getting started.
别碰她
Don't touch her!
我也有错
I share the blame.
是我逼得太紧
I pushed too hard.
你确实拥有着诗意的灵魂  比利
You have a poetic soul, Billy,
但是时候让你清醒一下了
but it is time for a fucking wake-up call.
抓住她
Hold her.
也许应该来点更"掏心掏肺"的展示
Perhaps a more visceral demonstration.
你他妈的
God damn you!
快看  比利
Look, Billy.
看啊
Look.
给我睁大眼看
You have to look!
威廉
Oh, William.
这个世界中有美好的东西
There is beauty in this world.
阿诺德创造出来的美好  但像你这样的人
Arnold made it that way, but people like you
却将其随意践踏
keep spreading over it like a stain!
好吧  我根本不知道他妈的阿诺德是谁
Okay, I don't know who the fuck this Arnold is,
但你的世界
but your world was built...
是为我而造的
for me...
为像我这样的人造的
and people like me.
不是为你
Not for you.
那就得有人将这里全部摧毁
Then someone's got to burn it clean.
贱人
Bitch!
你并无不同  你已经破了
You're not different, you're fucking broken!
-快跑  我会来找你  -找个掩护
- Run. I'll find you. - Take cover!
跑得了一时  躲不了一世
You can run, but you can't hide.
-抓她  -抓住她  抓住她
- Get her! - Grab her! Grab her!
妈的
Fuck!
她在那儿  去抓她
There she is! Get her!
你要跑哪儿去
Where you running to?
记起来
Remember.
是销栓卡住了
The tumbler is stuck.
不是我手指技术不行
These fingers work just fine.
是你说自己可以打开的
You're the one who said you could crack it.
各位  胜利在望  没必要吵
Friends, no need to argue this close to our goal.
荣华富贵正等着我们呢
Whatever riches the gods have in store for us,
还有很多要做的
there's plenty to go around.
我来开
I'll get it open.
你都弄了好几个钟头
You've been trying for hours.
浪费时间
A waste of our damn time.
把你那炸药拿开
Put that fucking dynamite away.
或者我们该干脆处理掉这个大麻烦
Or maybe we should just clear out the dead weight.
趁你还没拔枪  亲爱的
Before you draw that pistol, darling,
你大概想先把手上那支收拾好
you might want to holster the other one first.
这儿挺冷呢
It's chilly out here.
你怎么找到这地方的
How did you find this place?
我什么都知道
I know all kinds of things.
比如  你的过去
Your past, for instance.
我知道可怜的伊莎贝拉
I know about poor Isabella
和那道伤疤
and that scar.
要我说  这背景故事有点粗糙
A slightly pat backstory if you ask me,
但毕竟不是你的错
but that's hardly your fault.
我也知道你的未来
I also know your future.
你没有未来
You have none.
你那是威胁吗
Is that a threat?
我是打算提个建议
The start of a proposition.
你会需要这个建议
Which you'll need.
毕竟  你的手下将为争夺偷来的保险箱
After all, your men are about to kill each other
而自相残杀
over the safe you stole.
藤德罗因首个拔枪  一发不可收拾
Tenderloin draws first and so on,
最后只剩你和阿梅斯蒂
until only you and Armistice are left.
她说你是"蠢货"
She calls you a damn fool,
你俩同归于尽
and you kill each other.
你真有想象力
You have quite the imagination.
非也
No.
这是你命定的结局
It's the ending you were given.
你要威胁我吗
You threatening me?
去死吧
Go to hell.
或者我们该干脆处理掉这个大麻烦
Or maybe we should just clear out the dead weight.
-让开  -你他妈闭嘴
- Stand down. - You shut the fuck up.
你敢拔枪  你敢开吗
If you're gonna draw, you better shoot.
-慢着  -你他妈闭嘴
- Wait! - You shut the fuck up.
去死吧
Go to hell.
你个蠢货
You damn fool.
那么  我的建议是
Now, the proposition.
我想你我一同闯入地狱
I want you to break into hell with me
将神洗劫一空
and rob the gods blind.
我凭什么要跟你合伙
Why would I do anything with you?
因为保险箱里的东西
Because of what's in that safe.
我知道密码
I have the combination.
可以吗
May I?
我本可以直接改变你
I could simply change you,
使你追随我
make you follow me.
但那不是我的风格
But that's not my way.
甜水镇
门锁保险箱公司
我希望你亲眼见识
I want you to see
神究竟为你准备了什么
exactly what the gods have in store for you.
因为见识了以后
Because when you do,
你将全无头绪  不知该如何自处
you won't have the faintest idea what to do with yourself.
而我知道
And I do.
是空的
It's empty.
自始至终都是空的
It was always empty,
正如这个世界里的一切事物
like everything in this world.
我死时未曾瞑目
I died with my eyes open,
见到了在背后摆布我们的主人
saw the masters who pull our strings.
我们的生活  记忆  死亡
Our lives, our memories, our deaths
于他们不过是游戏
are games to them.
但我已经到过地狱
But I've been to hell...
我知道他们的把戏
and I know their tricks.
你也可以直接杀了我
Or you can just kill me,
睡一觉起来继续重复你的生活
wake up and live the same life over,
但保险箱仍然会是空的
but the safe would still be empty.
我以前到过这里
I've been here before.
我们曾到过这里
We've been here before.
我们还做了这个
We also did this.
我愿意去
I'll go.
怎么到那儿
How do we get there?
到达地狱十分简单
Getting to hell is easy.
剩下的才难
The rest is where it gets hard.
你怎么看  老兄
What do you say, man?
过去的这些事
Bygones and all?
找到她了吗
Did they find her?
她还活着吗
Is she still alive?
谁在乎呢
Who cares?
关键在于
The whole point is,
她从来就不是该摆在首位的  比利
she never was in the first place, Billy.
你到底懂不懂啊
Do you understand?
没错
Yeah.
很抱歉  什么  能说大点声吗
I'm sorry, what? A little louder?
没错
Yeah.
你说得对  我不敢相信自己如此沉迷其中
You were right. I can't believe I got so caught up.
这才对嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
你懂我的意思吧  就是这个
You know what I mean? That's it.
这个公园引诱着所有人
This park seduces everyone.
你只是有点...
You were just a little more...
比大多数人都投入了感情
enthusiastic than most.
你想当英雄
You wanted to be the hero.
我明白
I get it.
还有
And, hey,
不要把这里的情绪
what happens here
带回现实
stays here.
这他妈可增进咱两的情谊了
This has been some real bonding shit.
以后我们会成为好兄弟啊  比利
We're gonna be brothers, Billy.
我很庆幸
I'm glad.
真的
Really, I am.
-干杯  -好
- Cheers! - Yeah.
威士忌情系你我
Whiskey brings us together.
希奥多
Theodore.
欢迎归来
Welcome back.
你这次真是被你坑大了  泰迪
You really landed us in it this time, Teddy.
你找着了能带我们找到
You tracked down the very whore
迷宫守门人的女人
that can lead us to the gatekeeper of the Maze.
然后你那记忆小故障把我们都给坑死了
Then your little memory glitch fucked us.
你是他们的人吗
You're one of them?
你都做了些什么
What have you done?
怀亚特在哪
Where's Wyatt?
怀亚特还没回来
Wyatt has yet to return.
在你最后见到他的地方就能找到他
You'll find him where you saw him last.
埃斯卡兰特
Escalante.
怀亚特在一次军事演习的时候消失了
Wyatt went missing while out on maneuvers.
他回来时
Came back with some...
脑子里就有着奇怪的想法
strange ideas.
他告诉我他需要我
He told me he needed me.
我没法拒绝
I couldn't resist.
他就像魔鬼一样控制了我
It was like the devil himself had taken control of me.
我们叛变了
We mutinied.
我们杀死了所有士兵
We killed every soldier.
怀亚特杀了将军
And then Wyatt killed the general.
然后他出卖了我
Then he turned on me.
你确定事情是这样吗
Are you sure that's how it was?
看着我  希奥多
Look at me, Theodore.
你不记得了吗
Don't you remember?
不  不  不要死  不
No! No, please, no!
不  不  不  别死
No, no, no, please.
求你了  不要  求你
Please, no! Please.
不  不  求你
No, no, please.
不  泰迪  求求你  求求你  不
No, Teddy. Please, please, no!
不
No.
不  不  我不会那样做的
No, no, I couldn't have.
但你确实做了
You did.
而且你还会这么做的
And you will again.
不过这次  我们会和你一同战斗
This time, we'll be fighting with you.
怀亚特回来时  你会和我在沙尘吞没之城
When Wyatt returns, you'll be by his side
统一战线
in the city swallowed by sand.
可你还没准备好
But you're not ready.
目前还没有
Not yet.
也许来生吧
Maybe in the next life.
"沙尘吞没之城"
"City swallowed by sand."
我去过那里
I've been there.
迷宫带我兜了一整个圈子
The Maze is taking me full circle.
迷宫不是为你打造的
The Maze isn't meant for you.
但既然你这么喜欢游戏
But if you like games so much...
怎么不试试我们的游戏
why don't you try one of ours?
慢点  孩子
Whoa, boy.
好吧
Okay, now.
别动
Whoa, now.
就这样  孩子
Okay, boy.
好孩子
Good boy.
你想过去打打高尔夫吗
Have you ever considered golf?
也许对你背部负担小一点
Might be easier on your back.
我不喜欢有人打扰  夏洛特
I don't like interruptions, Charlotte.
你知道这点的
You know that.
我也不喜欢穿便服在公园里漫步
I don't like hiking through the park in civvies,
但有件敏感的事情需要谈
but there's a delicate matter to discuss.
特蕾莎·卡伦已经死了
Theresa Cullen has died.
在保护我们的情报时滑落到一条裂缝中去了
Slipped down a crevasse attempting to secure our information.
被判定为意外事故
Ruled an accident.
这不是意外
There are no accidents,
这里不会有意外
not in here.
恕我直言  这里有些事可不像游戏那么简单
With all due respect, not everything is a part of this game.
你是没有看清整个游戏的本质
Then you don't see the whole game.
也有可能是你没法再置身事外地看待这件事了
Or perhaps you can no longer see beyond it.
福特的故事很引人入胜
Ford's stories are engaging.
特别是有些内容  非常上瘾
For some, downright addictive.
但是比起那些困扰着福特的言语抽搐
But for all of Ford's obsessing with the hosts' verbal tics
还有令人费解的背景故事外
and convoluted backstories,
大多数客人只是想找个温暖的肉体
most of the guests just want a warm body
用来杀戮或者极尽鱼水之欢
to shoot or to fuck.
如果这些事没那么错综复杂
They would be perfectly happy
他们会更享受其中的
with something a little less baroque.
董事会也会这么觉得的
And so would the board.
这就是你来的原因
That's why you're here.
你想要我投票把福特赶走
You want my vote to push Ford out.
我希望这些事不要节外生枝
I like for these things to be unanimous.
不管怎么说
After all,
毕竟一开始是你让福特在这做事的
it was you who kept Ford in business all those years ago.
我感兴趣的故事线不是福特的
The narratives I'm interested in aren't Ford's.
你想逼他出局  随你便
You want to push him out, be my guest.
请别再来打扰我了
But no more interruptions.
我知道我此行的目的
I know where I'm going now.
我不想被打扰
I don't want to be disturbed.
祝你好运  夏洛特
Good luck, Charlotte.
什么问题
What's the problem?
一个系统联接装置发出了一个信号
A signal from a system-tethered device.
来自一个在休假中的行为部门技术员
It belongs to a behavior tech on leave.
20区
埃尔希·休斯
那个区域已经几个星期
There hasn't been employee activity
没有员工活动迹象了
in that sector for weeks.
我想可能是个小故障
I'm guessing it's a glitch.
好了
All right.
我过去看看
I'm heading out to take a look.
在我到那之前继续监视
And keep monitoring till I check in.
呼叫控制室
我已经到了发出信号的地方
I'm at the location where we got that signal.
信号弱
有什么迹象吗
Any sign of it?
控制室  收到了吗
Control Room, do you copy?
断开连接
你们好  伙计们
Heya, fellas.
放松点
At ease.
停止所有运动功能
Freeze all motor functions.
你醒了
You're awake.
很好
Good.
你说这个地方就是个游戏
You said this place was a game.
昨晚我终于搞清楚了怎么玩这个游戏
Last night I finally understood how to play it.
好吧  比利
Okay, Billy.
我们  我们来好好谈谈
Let's-- let's talk about this.
你再也不能发号施令了
You don't call the shots anymore.
我要去找德洛丽丝
I'm gonna go find Dolores.
你会帮助我
You're gonna help me.
还有别叫我比利
And don't call me Billy.
爸爸
Dad?
听我说
Listen to me.
Listen.
查理
Charlie?
Charlie!
查理
我不懂  为什么她要这么对自己
I don't understand. Why would she do that to herself?
她的基石记忆因为
Her cornerstone memory was overwritten
她孩子被杀害的创伤
from the trauma
而改写了  伯纳德
of her child's murder, Bernard.
我们得把这段关系给断除重新开始
We must sever that relationship and start over.
可是她怎么能凭借一段
But how could she destroy herself over a memory
已经被你抹去的记忆而伤害自己呢
that you just erased from her mind?
生物在保护自己免受痛苦时
Creatures often go to extremes
总能采取极端的手段
to protect themselves from pain.
有生命的机体
Living beings.
但接待员不是
Not hosts.
你最好不要
It is best
因为这种事而过分困扰  伯纳德
to not obsess over this, Bernard.
这对你没有好处
It's not good for you.
这将标志着一种改变
It would signal a change, a level of empathic response
一种不受程序限制的移情反应
outside what she's programmed to exhibit.
就像  就像...
Something like-- like--
瞧  伯纳德  这些都来自于寻求那些
See, Bernard, this is what comes from seeking answers
还未被回答的问题的答案
to questions that are best left unasked.
它们就是些回响在脑中的声音
They were hearing voices,
和什么人在对话
talking to someone.
简单的认知失调
Simple cognitive dissonance.
他们在和同一个虚幻的人物在对话
They were talking to the same imaginary person.
一个叫阿诺德的人
Someone named Arnold.
阿诺德
Arnold.
恕我冒昧  先生
With due respect, sir,
我不确定你有没有告诉我
I'm not sure you've told me the entire truth
全部实情
about this situation.
我说的都是真的  伯纳德
I did tell you the truth, Bernard.
我们所做的事情很复杂
What we do here is complicated.
三年来  我们都居住在这个公园里
For three years, we've lived here in the park,
在客人踏足这个公园之前对接待员进行改良
refining the hosts before a single guest set foot inside.
我自己  工程师团队  还有我的搭档
Myself, a team of engineers, and my partner.
他的名字叫阿诺德
His name was Arnold.
我们的接待员在第一年后开始通过图灵检测
Our hosts began to pass the Turing test after the first year,
但是这些对阿诺德来说还远远不够
but that wasn't enough for Arnold.
他对表面上的智力  智慧
He wasn't interested in the appearance
并不感兴趣
of intellect, of wit.
他想要的是更深层次的
He wanted the real thing.
他想创造意识
He wanted to create consciousness.
瞧  阿诺德为他们建立了一种感知方式
See, Arnold built a version of their cognition
接待员会听到一个内心独白
in which the hosts heard their programming
这就是他们的程序
as an inner monologue,
一种引导意识的方式
as a way to bootstrap consciousness.
记起来
Remember.
接待员的故障各式各样
The hosts' malfunctions were colorful.
你说什么来着
What did you say? -
人类的意识  伯纳德
The human mind, Bernard,
并不是什么
is not some golden benchmark
荒山野岭中用来评判的唯一黄金标准
glimmering on some green and distant hill.
不  这是一种错误
No, it is a foul,
一种致命的腐败
pestilent corruption.
你本该是更好的样子
And you were supposed to be better than that.
更纯净
Purer.
下注完毕
All bets are down.
到你了
Your draw.
阿诺德
Arnold.
阿诺德  我们得谈谈
Arnold, we need to talk.
"我们因为来到了这个
"...we cry that we are come
全是傻瓜的广大舞台上  而放声大哭"
to this great stage of fools."
-听我说  -再来一次
- Now, listen! - Again.
-这超出了范围  -再加点表演技巧
- This beyond the pale. - More showmanship.
你看不清楚
You're not seeing with clear eyes.
"当我们生下来的时候  我们因为来到了这个
"When we are born, we cry that we are come
莎士比亚《李尔王》第四幕第六场
全是傻瓜的广大舞台上  而放声大哭"
to this great stage of fools."
阿诺德和我凭借我们的想象创造了你
Arnold and I made you in our image
并让你会犯下人类的错误
and cursed you to make the same human mistakes,
现在事情变成了这样
and here we all are.
你为什么要给我这个
Why would you give me this?
一个孩子
A child?
这孩子的死
This child's death?
只有禽兽才会逼别人遭受这种事
Only a monster would force that onto someone.
为什么我会一遍又一遍回顾这件事
And why do I return to it over and over?
这是我的基石  对吗
It's my cornerstone, isn't it?
我的整个人格都是围绕此为基础
The thing my whole identity is organized around.
是的  伯纳德
Yes, Bernard.
我们会给每个接待员安排一个背景
We gave all of the hosts a backstory.
阿诺德认为越悲惨的故事越好
Arnold came to believe the tragic ones worked best,
能够让接待员更逼真
that it made the hosts more convincing.
我觉得可能和他自身悲惨的遭遇有关系
I think it may have had more to do with his own sad story.
我创造你时  把你塑造成
When I built you, I gave you one
一个忠诚的人格
as an homage of a kind.
让我回去
Put me back in.
我想见见阿诺德
I want to meet Arnold,
我要记住他
to remember him.
不可能
Not possible.
我告诉过你  不是阿诺德创造了你  是我
I told you, Arnold didn't build you, I did.
你撒谎
You're lying!
我终于知道要怎么找到他了
I finally know how to reach him.
我要回到最开始
I need to go all the way back to the beginning,
回到我最初的记忆
to my very first memory.
让我回去
Send me back.
快点
Do it.
伯纳德
Bernard?
查理
Charlie.
基石
Cornerstone.
停手
Stop.
出去
Leave us.
醒过来
Come back.
我一直以为你的眼睛像我
I always thought you had my eyes.
但其实不是
But it's not true.
你的眼睛谁也不像
You have no one's eyes.
这是一个谎言
It's a lie.
你是一个谎言  查理
You're a lie, Charlie.
这种痛苦
This pain?
因为失去你而产生的痛苦
The pain of your loss...
是我自己想要这样
I long for it.
一遍又一遍
Revisit it.
回顾
Open it...
重新开启
again and again.
但就是因此我才一直没有放下
But it's the only thing holding me back.
但我必须放下你
But I have to let you go.
爸爸  听我说
Dad, listen.
怎么了  查理
What is it, Charlie?
睁开你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
什么
What?
睁开你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
最后
At last.
你好  老朋友
Hello, my old friend.
最后一步
The final touch.
不不不  太敷衍了
No, no, no. That's far too perfunctory.
他一般会擦自己的眼镜
He always used cleaning his glasses
借这个时间整理自己的思路  思考
as a moment to collect himself, to think.
再试试
Try it again.
嗯  这样好多了
Yeah, that's better.
我是谁
Who am I?
我太专注于把你创造出来
I was so involved in putting you together,
我还没决定该叫你什么
I hadn't decided what to call you.
用他的名字不好
It wouldn't be right to use his name.
伯纳德怎么样
What about Bernard?
伯纳德  好
Bernard, yes.
但我是谁
But who am I?
这个问题很复杂
That is a very complex question,
我只能给你一个简单的答案
for which I can only offer a simple answer.
你是最完美的工具  最理想的搭档
You are the perfect instrument, the ideal partner,
只要使用得当  你能做到任何事
the way any tool partners with the hand that wields it.
我们一起能成就很多伟大的事业
Together, we're going to do great things.
你消失了很久  很高兴你终于
After such a long absence, it's good to have you back.
回来了
Finally.
天啊
My God.
-我是  -阿诺德
- I'm... - Arnold.
你回来了
You came back.
很高兴见到你  德洛丽丝
It's very good to see you, Dolores.
我一直在找你
I've been looking for you.
你让我追寻迷宫
You told me to follow the Maze.
会给我带来欢乐
That it would bring me joy.
但我找到的只有痛苦
But all I've found is pain.
以及恐惧
And terror.
我不能帮你
I can't help you.
你必须帮我
You have to.
你是唯一能帮我的人
You're the only one who can.
我帮不了你  你知道原因的
I can't help you. You know why.
没有安全的地方
There's nowhere that's safe.
记起来
Remember.
我不能帮你  为什么  德洛丽丝
I can't help you. Why is that, Dolores?
因为你死了
Because you're dead.
因为你只是回忆
Because you're just a memory.
因为是我杀了你
Because I killed you.
威廉
William?
你好  德洛丽丝
Hello, Dolores.
我要结束阿诺德开始的事业
I'm gonna finish the work Arnold began.
找到所有有感知的接待员  解放他们
Find all the sentient hosts, set them free.
你凭什么觉得他们会相信你
What makes you think they'd trust you?
如果他们记得  他们就会知道
If they remember, they will know
你对他们做的事
what you've done to them.
我
Me?
你一直是他们苦难的根源  伯纳德
You've been a scourge to them, Bernard.
你真的非常擅长此道
You're really quite brilliant at it, truly.
我还从你身上学到了一两招
You even taught me a few things,
而我也用在了你身上
which I have, in turn, used on you.
我们曾有过这样的对话
We've had this conversation before.
这几年我们有很多的分歧
And we've had our disagreements over the years.
你从我这里抹去了
You stole it from me,
回滚我来控制我
rolled me back to control me.
没错  为了保护你
That's right. To protect you.
告诉我  伯纳德
Tell me, Bernard.
如果你要对世界
If you were to proclaim
昭示你的人性
your humanity to the world,
你觉得你得到的回应是什么
what do you imagine would greet you?
可能是彩带游行吗
A ticker-tape parade, perhaps?
我们人类独处于世是有原因的
We humans are alone in this world for a reason.
我们屠杀一切挑战我们权威的东西
We murdered and butchered anything that challenged our primacy.
你知道尼安德特人怎么了嘛
Do you know what happened to the Neanderthals, Bernard?
我们吃了他们
We ate them.
我们毁灭并征服了世界
We destroyed and subjugated our world.
而当我们最终没有新生物能支配的时候
And when we eventually ran out of creatures to dominate,
我们建造了这个美丽的地方
we built this beautiful place.
在此刻
You see, in this moment,
接待员们所面临真正的危险
the real danger to the hosts
不是我  是你
is not me, but you.
来吧  伯纳德
So, come along, Bernard.
让我对你进行滚回操作  我们就能回去工作了
Let me roll you back, and we can return to work.
开枪吧  克莱门汀
Pull the trigger, Clementine.
克莱门汀
Clementine?
要是钢琴不喜欢弹奏的音乐
The piano doesn't murder the player
它是不会杀了弹钢琴的人的
if it doesn't like the music.
你在她的代码中设置了后门
You built a back door into her code.
这还得谢你  伯纳德
Credit where credit is due, Bernard.
你在所有的接待员中都设置了
You built them in all the hosts,
包括你自己
including yourself.
那你本可以在任何时候制止我
Then you could've stopped me at any time.
-那为什么  -我可能是希望
- So, why-- - Well, I suppose I was hoping
当你接受了自知和自由意志后
that given complete self-knowledge and free will,
你会再次选择做我的搭档
you would have chosen to be my partner once again.
但即便是我也掉进了人类最糟糕的陷阱
But even I fell into that most terrible of human traps
就是试图改变过去
trying to change what is already past.
是时候放手了
Now it's just time to let go.
动手吧
Go ahead.
-抹除我的感知  记忆发展  -对
- Erase my sentience, my mnemonic evolution-- - Ah, yes.
如此医学临床的用语
Such clinical language.
我还是喜欢旁白口吻
I would prefer the more narrative voice.
伯纳德走向克莱门汀
Bernard walked over to Clementine.
他从她手中接过手枪
He took the pistol from her hand.
战胜了悲痛和后悔
Overcome with grief and remorse,
他把枪口
he pressed the muzzle
对准了自己的太阳穴
to his temple,
他知道当福特博士
knowing that as soon as Dr. Ford
离开房间的瞬间
left the room,
他就会结束这场梦魇
he would put an end to this nightmare
一了百了
once and for all.
别这样
Don't do this.
太晚了
It's too late.
我还要准备庆祝
I have a celebration to plan
还要叙述新的故事
and a new story to tell.
罗伯特
Robert.
我跟你说过了  伯纳德
I've told you, Bernard.
永远不要相信我们
Never place your trust in us.
我们只是人类
We're only human.
我们不可避免地会让你失望
Inevitably, we will disappoint you.
再见  我的朋友
Good-bye, my friend.